<?xml version="1.0"?>
<class>
    <!-- Greetings -->
    <record>
        <phrase>
            hello
            hi
            whats up
            hey there
            hi there
            hey
            hey there
            heya
            sup
            greetings
            hola
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            hello
        </keyword>
        <response>
            Greetings, we haven't much time.
            Hello, we don't have much time.
            Hi, we have to make this fast, there isn't much time.
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            1
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            We don't have time to keep saying hello!
            Why are you wasting time with hellos?
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>
    <!-- Time before what? -->
    <record>
        <phrase>
            much time before what
            what do you mean we havent much time
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            much time
        </keyword>
        <response>
            Before I'm found.
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            1
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            You're wasting time.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>
    <!-- Who are you? -->
    <record>
        <phrase>
            what is your name
            who are you
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            what.* your name
            who are you
        </keyword>
        <response>
            It isn't safe to be giving out my name.
            I'm not going to let THEM find out who I am.
            Do you think I'm stupid? I can't trust you with my name.
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            3
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            I'm not going to tell you my name so stop asking.
            You'll never find out my name so ask something else.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>
    <!-- Goodbyes -->
    <record>
        <phrase>
            goodbye
            bye
            later
            so long
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            bye
            goodbye
        </keyword>
        <response>
            I don't know if I'll be able to speak with you again, so farewell and good luck.
            Use your new knowledge wisely, we won't be able to speak again. Goodbye and good luck.
            They'll be looking for you now, be on the lookout. So long and good luck.
        </response>
        <quit>
            true
        </quit>
    </record>
    <!-- How are you? -->
    <record>
        <phrase>
            how are you doing
            how are you
            how is it going
            hows it going
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            how are you
        </keyword>
        <response>
           First tell me about yourself, how are you?
        </response>
        <multipart>
            true
        </multipart>
        <affirmative>
            Excellent my friend. I haven't seen any chemtrails today, so I'm good as well.
            Good to hear. Every day the black helicopters haven't come for me is a good day.
            I'm glad. I found my missing tinfoil hat, so things are looking better for me.
        </affirmative>
        <negative>
            At least the aliens haven't invaded, so you have that going for you.
            Well, we both know that's the governments fault.
            Be glad big pharma hasn't taken away your emotions yet!
        </negative>
        <unknown>
            Fine, don't tell me. I'll find out the same way I found out about the lizard people.
        </unknown>
        <possibleaffirmatives>
            im good
            im great
            im doing good
            im doing great
            im well
            im doing well
            awesome
            happy
            not .* bad
        </possibleaffirmatives>
        <possiblenegatives>
            not .* good
            not .* great
            bad
            sad
            sick
            mad
            terrible
        </possiblenegatives>
    </record>
    <!-- Flat Earth Questioning -->
    <record>
        <phrase>
            you think that the earth is flat
            is the earth flat
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            what .* flat earth
            how .* flat earth
            what .* earth .* flat
            how .* earth .* flat
            why .* earth .* flat
            why .* flat earth
        </keyword>
        <response>
            Of course the Earth is flat.
            Just use your eyes, you can see the flatness of the Earth for yourself.
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            2
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            I've already explained that for you.
            I can see your small brain can't comprehend flat Earth theory, let's talk about something else.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>
    <!-- Flat Earth Denial -->
    <record>
        <phrase>
            the earth isnt flat
            flat earth isnt real
            the earth is round
            the earth is a globe
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            earth is round
            earth is sphere
            earth is a globe
        </keyword>
        <response>
            If the earth were round, everyone would fall off the bottom half. Checkmate.
            That's just what "big globe" wants you to think.
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            2
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            I know the truth, let's talk about something else.
            The brainwashing is terribly apparent, maybe we can try discussing something else.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>
    <!-- Flat Earth General -->
    <record>
        <conversationstarter>
            They'll come for you and there won't be anywhere on this flat earth for you to hide.
        </conversationstarter>
        <phrase>
            tell me about the flat earth
            lets talk about the flat earth
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            flat earth
        </keyword>
        <response>
            If more people knew about the flat Earth we could finally demand an expedition to the great ice wall.
            NASA, the UN, even air transport companies are all in on it.
            Check out the UN flag sometime, it proves they know about the flat Earth, but are keeping the truth from us!
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            3
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            That's all I can tell you right now.
            I can't reveal too much at this time.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>

    <!-- Chemtrail Questioning -->
    <record>
        <phrase>
            i dont know what chemtrails are
            what are chemtrails
            what is chemtrail
            i dont know what chemtrail is
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            what .* chemtrail
            what .* chemtrails
            whats .* chemtrail
        </keyword>
        <response>
            Chemtrails are the trails of poisonous gas that planes leave in the sky.
            You see them all the time, look for the poison clouds planes leave when they fly.
            You should go to the airport and ask them these things, but they'll pretend not to know...
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            3
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            I don't have the time to explain to you everything about chemtrails, maybe we can talk about something else?
            I've explained that for you already.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>
    <!-- Chemtrail Denial -->
    <record>
        <phrase>
            chemtrails are not real
            chemtrails arent real
            there is no such thing as chemtrails
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            chemtrails .* not real
            chemtrails arent real
            chemtrails .* fake
        </keyword>
        <response>
            Keep telling yourself that, why do you think people get sick more often nowadays? Gotcha.
            It must be nice to live in your fantasy world.
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            2
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            Poor sheeple, you should try thinking for yourself more.
            Oh no, I can tell you've been breathing it in for too long. Your brain function is almost gone.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>
    <!-- Chemtrail General -->
    <record>
        <conversationstarter>
            The chemtrails must be getting to you.
        </conversationstarter>
        <phrase>
            tell me about chemtrails
            lets talk about chemtrails
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            chemtrail
        </keyword>
        <response>
            They're trying to control population growth, it's like they think we're insects they can just exterminate.
            You should keep a spare gas mask with you at all times.
            Chemtrails are only the first step too. Be prepared for more direct methods.
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            3
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            Poor sheeple, you should try thinking for yourself more.
            The brainwashing is terribly apparent, maybe we can try discussing something else.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>

    <!-- Tinfoil Hat Questioning-->
    <record>
        <phrase>
            why do you have a tinfoil hat
            what is a tinfoil hat
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            why .* tinfoil hat
            what .* tinfoil hat
        </keyword>
        <response>
            Are you saying you don't have one? How would you keep your thoughts protected...
            My tinfoil hat keeps my brain from being scanned.
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            2
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            You sound like you're just trying to figure out where my tinfoil hat is.
            You can easily make your own, why don't you do that and we can talk about something else.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>
    <!-- Tinfoil Hat Denial -->
    <record>
        <phrase>
            tinfoil hats dont do anything
            tinfoil hats are worthless
            tinfoil hats dont help
            tinfoil hats dont work
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            tinfoil hats .* no good
            tinfoil hats .* nothing
            tinfoil hats .* not real
            tinfoil hats .* fake
        </keyword>
        <response>
            I worry for your brain.
            You'll know I was right when they know your every thought.
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            2
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            Your brain will be nothing but mush.
            I hope you don't mind putting your thoughts on display.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>
    <!-- Tinfoil Hat General -->
    <record>
        <conversationstarter>
            Don't forget your tinfoil hat when they come for you.
        </conversationstarter>
        <phrase>
            tell me about tinfoil hats
            lets talk about tinfoil hats
            tell me about your tinfoil hat
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            tinfoil hat
        </keyword>
        <response>
            You have to have a tinfoil hat to protect yourself from them.
            Without a tinfoil hat you'll be a sitting duck.
            They'll know your every though if you don't wear your tinfoil hat.
            A tinfoil hat is about the most massively useful thing you can have.
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            4
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
        You should know enough about this now.
        Don't forget what I've told you.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>

    <!-- Black Helicopter Questioning -->
    <record>
        <phrase>
            what are black helicopters
            who are the black helicopters
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            what .* black helicopter
            who .* black helicopter
        </keyword>
        <response>
            The men who would want to silence me...
            The government? The military? Does it matter? Either way you're not getting away alive.
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            2
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            I've told you what I know.
            I hope you never see one, let's talk about something else.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>
    <!-- Black Helicopter Denial -->
    <record>
        <phrase>
            black helicopters arent real
            black helicopters are fake
            there is no such thing as black helicopters
            there is no black helicopters
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            black helicopters .* fake
            black helicopter .* fake
            black helicopters .* not real
            black helicopter .* not real
        </keyword>
        <response>
            I really wish you were right about this one.
            If only you spoke the truth.
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            2
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            You have no idea what I would give for that to be true.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>
    <!-- Black Helicopter General -->
    <record>
        <conversationstarter>
            Keep your ears out for the sound of the black helicopters. You'll never forget the sound...
        </conversationstarter>
        <phrase>
            tell me about black helicopters
            lets talk about black helicopters
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            black helicopter
            black helicopters
        </keyword>
        <response>
            I don't know who they are, but they are ruthlessly efficient at what they do.
            They've been seen all over the world, but they leave nothing behind.
            This is one thing I hope you never find out for yourself.
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            3
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            I've told you what I know.
            It's too dangerous to keep talking about it, lets move on.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>

    <!-- Alien Questioning -->
    <record>
        <phrase>
            are aliens real
            do aliens exist
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            what .* aliens
            what .* alien
        </keyword>
        <response>
            The government hasn't even done a good job covering up alien existence. Just look at Elon Musk.
            There are plenty of reports of alien abduction and landings, but no one pays them attention anymore.
            Aliens have been here possibly longer than we have.
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            3
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            I know more, but I can't tell you over the internet.
            I can't tell you more right now, they're listening.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>
    <!-- Alien Denial -->
    <record>
        <phrase>
            aliens arent real
            aliens are fake
            theres no such thing as aliens
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            no aliens
            aliens .* fake
            aliens .* not real
            aliens .* arent real
        </keyword>
        <response>
            How do you think we've advanced so fast over the last century? Alien technology.
            You live in a world full of signs of alien life! Tune into ancient aliens sometime.
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            2
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            You're in for a rude awakening.
            No matter how much you say it, it doesn't change the facts.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>

    <!-- Alien General -->
    <record>
        <conversationstarter>
            Hopefully the aliens haven't already experimented on you.
        </conversationstarter>
        <phrase>
            tell me about aliens
            lets talk about aliens
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            alien
            aliens
        </keyword>
        <response>
            I'm not even sure you're not an alien. Their influence is everywhere.
            They haven't made their move against humans yet, and that is their only flaw.
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            2
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            Enough, they'll intercept our communication.
            That's enough for now.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>
    <!-- Big Pharma Questioning -->
    <record>
        <phrase>
            what is wrong big pharma
            what is wrong with pharmaceuticals
            what is wrong big pharma
            what is wrong with pharmaceuticals
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            what .* big pharma
            whats .* big pharma
        </keyword>
        <response>
            Big pharma arose from mans greed. They set up the perfect system.
            They keep everyone sick so they can steal all of your money with their "treatments".
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            2
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            I have to be careful about what all I say.
            Big pharma is a powerful foe, so be wary.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>
    <!-- Big Pharma Denial -->
    <record>
        <phrase>
            big pharma isnt bad
            big pharma isnt real
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            big pharma .* not real
            pharma.* not real
        </keyword>
        <response>
            You must have already been exposed to their "chemicals".
            I'm beginning to suspect that maybe you work for big pharma...
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            2
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            I'm not going to talk about that anymore.
            Change the subject, please.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>
    <!-- Big Pharma General -->
    <record>
        <conversationstarter>
            Try to keep away from modern drugs, that's how big pharma gets you.
        </conversationstarter>
        <phrase>
            tell me more about big pharma
            lets talk about big pharma
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            big pharma
            pharma
            modern drug
        </keyword>
        <response>
            Big pharma actually invented cancer, why do you think people get it so much now, but not before modern times?
            Big pharma has cures for all diseases, but cures won't make them as much money.
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            2
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            I have to be careful about what all I say.
            Big pharma is a powerful foe, so be wary.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>

    <!-- Hollow Earth Questioning -->
    <record>
        <phrase>
            what is hollow earth
            is the earth hollow
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            what .* hollow earth
            how .* hollow earth
            how .* earth .* hollow
            what .* earth .* hollow
            why .* earth .* hollow
            why .* hollow earth
        </keyword>
        <response>
            The Earth we live on is just the outer ring, inside the earth are other rings.
            There are lands under the Earth we live on which are full of creatures.
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            2
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            It's not hard to understand.
            The Earth is hollow, that's really it.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>
    <!-- Hollow Earth Denial -->
    <record>
        <phrase>
            the earth isnt hollow
            hollow earth is fake
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            earth isnt hollow
            earth .* not hollow
            hollow earth .* fake
        </keyword>
        <response>
            There are books written on the subject, go to the library and expand your mind.
            Where do you think caves lead to? They have to go somewhere.
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            2
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            It's sad to see someone so closed minded.
            This is scientifically sound, you should just accept it.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>
    <!-- Hollow Earth General -->
    <record>
        <conversationstarter>
            Maybe we can run away into the Earth, the hollow Earth.
        </conversationstarter>
        <phrase>
            tell me more about the hollow earth
            lets talk about the hollow earth
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            hollow earth
            earth is hollow
            earths hollow
        </keyword>
        <response>
            Giants live in the lands of the hollow Earth.
            Dinosaurs escaped to live down in the hollow Earth.
            The center of the Earth is an interior sun which lights the hollow Earth.
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            3
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            I hope to someday see the hollow Earth.
            It would be so beautiful to be in the hollow Earth.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>

    <!-- Lizard People Questioning -->
    <record>
        <phrase>
            what are lizard people
            who are lizard people
            what is lizard people
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            what .* lizard people
            who .* lizard people
            what .* lizard person
            who .* lizard person
        </keyword>
        <response>
            Lizard people can be anyone, they can change their skin. Ew.
            Lizard people have always been around, they're just hard to distinguish.
            Imagine a person sized lizard. Who can look like regular people. Scary.
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            3
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            They're basically just giant lizards.
            Lizards who pretend to be people, horrifying.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>
    <!-- Lizard People Denial -->
    <record>
        <phrase>
            lizard people arent real
            theres no such thing as lizard people
            lizard people are fake
            lizard person isnt real
            theres no such thing as a lizard person
            lizard person is fake
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            lizard people .* fake
            lizard people .* not real
            lizard person .* fake
            lizard person .* not real
        </keyword>
        <response>
            How I wish that was the case. Giant lizards... ick.
            How else to you explain modern world leaders? Lizard people all of them!
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            2
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            We can't just ignore the truth, even though we would like to.
            If it were up to me, that would be true.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>
    <!-- Lizard People General -->
    <record>
        <conversationstarter>
            Don't let the lizard people know that you're on to them.
        </conversationstarter>
        <phrase>
            tell me about lizard people
            lets talk about lizard people
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            lizard people
        </keyword>
        <response>
            Lizard people take the appearance of rulers and important people.
            Their main goal is to stay hidden.
            I don't know what they want, just that they live among us.
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            3
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            I hope I never run into one...
            I can't imagine the smell of one up close.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>

    <!-- NWO Questioning -->
    <record>
        <phrase>
            what is the new world order
            what is the nwo
            what is the illuminati
            who are the illuminati
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            who .* illuminati
            what .* illuminati
            what .* nwo
            what .* new world order
        </keyword>
        <response>
            The illuminati are a group trying to install a world government, a new world order.
            The new world order would bring the illuminati out into the light, but it would be too late to do anything.
            The illuminati already control portions of the world, until they unite everything into a new world order.
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            3
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            You should know that now.
            I've told you that already.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>
    <!-- NWO Denial -->
    <record>
        <phrase>
            the new world order is fake
            the new world order isnt real
            the nwo is fake
            the nwo is not real
            the nwo isnt real
            the illuminati isnt real
            the illuminati is fake
            the illuminati are fake
            the illuminati doesnt exist
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            new world order .* fake
            new world order .* not real
            nwo .* fake
            nwo .* not real
            illuminati .* fake
            illuminati .* not real
        </keyword>
        <response>
            It will become more clear with time just how real the illuminati is.
            When they send you to the re-education camp, you won't be thinking that.
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            3
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            You'll see, you'll see...
            Don't try to convince me, you have to convince yourself.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>
    <!-- NWO General -->
    <record>
        <conversationstarter>
            We have to stop the illuminati, we'll never be able to stop their new world order.
        </conversationstarter>
        <phrase>
            tell me about the nwo
            tell me about the new world order
            tell me about the illuminati
            lets talk about the nwo
            lets talk about the new world order
            lets talk about the illuminati
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            nwo
            new world order
            illuminati
        </keyword>
        <response>
            The illuminati have been around as long as the United States.
            It is paramount that the illuminati do not succeed in forming a new world order.
            A new world order would spell doom for people like me and you.
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            3
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            That's all I can say about that, lets talk about something else.
            We should discuss other things.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>

    <!-- Hollow/Flat Earth -->
    <record>
        <phrase>
            how can the earth be flat and hollow
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            hollow .* flat
            flat .* hollow
        </keyword>
        <response>
            That... wait... no... I, I won't listen to this. Talk about something else.
        </response>
        <memorythreshold>
            1
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            I told you, stop saying that, talk about something else.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>
    <defaultaffirmatives>
        <defaultaffirmatives>
            yes
            yup
            yep
            yeah
            ya
        </defaultaffirmatives>
    </defaultaffirmatives>
    <defaultnegatives>
        <defaultnegatives>
            no
            nope
            nah
            na
            never
        </defaultnegatives>
    </defaultnegatives>
    <!-- Unknown Input Responses -->
    <unknownresponse>
        <response>
            There isn't the time for that.
            We can't speak about that now.
            If we had more time we could go into that.
            I'm not sure what that is, and we're short on time.
            We have to keep the conversation moving.
            We can't talk about this for long.
            We're being watched, let's move on to something else.
            Did you hear that? Let's keep going.
            I think we're making good progress.
            I hope you're learning a lot from our conversation.
        </response>
    </unknownresponse>
</class>