<?xml version="1.0"?>

<data>
	<connotations>
		<connotation>
			<key>normal</key>
			<trigger>
				fine
				alright
			</trigger>
			<response>
			you dont look excited. Everything alright ? Game is on.
			Hey chill up ! we are having wonderful discussion.   
			Seems like you are not too much into football. Can you believe football is like a religion in other countries.
			Just keep up with the matches. you will find the game exciting and players too.	
			Cmon. You dont wanna see Messi playing being on the stadium. How cool that be !
			Dont wanna know about football facts?
			</response>
		</connotation>
		<connotation>
			<key>curious</key>
			<trigger>
				nice
				great
				wonderful
			</trigger>
			<response>
			I am happy that you are excited.
			Sounds great ! we need to move fast ! I need to go to see the match soon!
			We should talk about this more. You are great!
			Nice to hear that you like this.
			</response>
		</connotation>
		<connotation>
			<key>cold</key>
			<trigger>
				bad
				terrible
				horrible
				worse
				rough
				gross
			</trigger>
			<response>
			Hey, dont be cold . we are just talking. I am not asking for your kidney haha...
		Hey. lets warm up. After all ,we are talking about football
		Hey. are you not interested? thats terrible.lemme share some exciting facts about football
		Yeah ! football sometimes become the dirty game. You should watch El Classico fights.
		But you are still breathing.You should play football to have more fun !
			</response>
		</connotation>
	</connotations>

	<!-- Conversation starters based on tracked time and unknown responses triggered -->
	<modes>
		<mode>
			how you holding up ? don't you want to talk about match?
			I guess you are not bored about soccer ?
			I cant wait to talk about soccer more.
			i wont be available every time. so lets do it.
		</mode>
		<mode>
			Its cold . Where is your sweater?. It seems like it will rain too! Oh God !
			The weather looks great ! 
			I feel like i should have played more soccer when i was child.
			I liked to get more goals when i play like messi does.
			If i could meet one footballer it would be Messi.
		</mode>
		<mode>
			I dont have much time now. I will see you at UNM someday.
			Anymore you wanna know. hurry up!.
			I felt wonderful talking to you.
			would i be able to talk to you again ?
			I hope you will be around.
		</mode>
	</modes>

	<reaction>
	    <reaction>
		oh ok. 
		great!
		ah..
		I don’t  mind whatever it is .
		aw sounds good.
		Yeah. We can do that.
		God is crazy ! 
		Sometimes! You dont know whats gonna happen.
		This world is unbelievable.
		football is round so is earth... haha
		That's gross hoho.
		</reaction>
	</reaction>

	<!-- <record> <keywords> hi hola hello </keywords> <phrases> </phrases> 
		<response> </response> </record> -->
	<class>
	<record>
        <phrase>
            goodbye
            bye
            later
        </phrase>
        <keyword>
            bye
            goodbye
        </keyword>
        <response>
           It was great talking to you ! Sayo nara !
           HASTA LA VISTA ! Good Day !
           Good bye mate ! 
        </response>
        <quit>
            true
        </quit>
    </record>
    
    <record>
            <keyword>
            hello
            hola
        </keyword>
        <phrase>
            hi,how are you doing?
            hi,how are you?
            hi,how is it going?
            hi there, how are things going?
			How is it going
			how you doing
			how are you doing
        </phrase>
        <response>
          Hi, ! how you doing mate ?
          Hi, Great to see you! I am doing good ! How are things going with you?
          whats up.I am not doing bad. You?
          I am doing good. you ?
			Hi,I am good. You seem great too. are you ?
				Yeah. its not bad. yours ?
				Things are going well for me. how is it for you ?
        </response>
        <multipart>
            true
        </multipart>
        <affirmative>
           Good to hear that ! Did you watch the laliga today?
           Happy to hear ! Did Messi scored a goal in todays match? Barcelona should have won today.
           awesome that you are doing well ! football boots have become quite expensive. 
           Wow great you are well ! did you get the news today. Premier Leagues are going to start soon ! 
           Good to hear ! Things are getting pretty intense in soccer nowadays! 
        </affirmative>
        <negative>
            Awww ! But you are still alive to talk about football. arent you mate
            Shit happens ! . You should play soccer. It makes you feel great I bet .
            Hope all will be good !. Yah ! Messi got injured too!
            Look the brighter side ! you look gorgeous like football stars!        
        </negative>
        <unknown>
           Not telling me ! No worries. Just tell me how is soccer going? We can at least talk about that
           Its ok you will figure out what you are feeling later? Meanwhile i am going to stadium after a while.
        </unknown>
        <possibleaffirmatives>
            im good
            im great
            im doing good
            im doing great
            im well
            im doing well
            awesome
            happy
            good
            great
            fine
        </possibleaffirmatives>
        <possiblenegatives>
            not good
            bad
            sad
            sick
            mad
            terrible
        </possiblenegatives>
        <memorythreshold>
            1
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            Would you keep saying hello or wanna move to soccer stuffs.
            We already said ! lets talk about football. I mean your soccer thing.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>
    <record>
            <keyword>
           game
           tonite
           live
        </keyword>
        <phrase>
          tonight game
          tonight match
        </phrase>
        <response>
        Would you like to watch tonight match with me. You know popcorn and beer! Its el classico
        What about live match today. Its between madrid and barcelona. Super coool!!!!
        </response>
        <multipart>
            true
        </multipart>
        <affirmative>
           Good to hear that ! I will let you know the time and venue
           I am happy i will be watching match with you tonite. I will grab some beer
           I wasnot hoping that you will like to join. Welcome home tonite dude !
        </affirmative>
        <negative>
            Oh! no worries we can do it next time. We have other important match coming.
            I thought you would like watch soccer as much i do. Never mind
            Ok. You seem busy. we will make this work out next time my place.     
        </negative>
        <unknown>
           Busy ! No worries. Just tell me how is soccer going? 
          We can do match instead? or we can go for hike then lol...i hate hiking though. I like running with football boot lol
        </unknown>
        <possibleaffirmatives>
           great
           good
           wonderful
           exciting
           free
        </possibleaffirmatives>
        <possiblenegatives>
            busy
            work
            bad
            terrible
            homework
            office
            church
        </possiblenegatives>
        <memorythreshold>
            1
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            Hey didnt we talk abou that already! we can jump to other stuffs. Ask me anything dude!
            I dont wanna talk about it again. I will check with other friend for upcoming match.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>
    
    <record>
            <keyword>
            match
            tournament
            competition
            boot
        </keyword>
        <phrase>
         the match
         the tournament
         the competition
        </phrase>
        <response>
         How about we have a football match some day?
         Would you like to go for match? We have UNM pitch
         Lets have your team and my team play match this weekend?
         Bring you football boot for upcoming match. How does that sound?
        </response>
        <multipart>
            true
        </multipart>
        <affirmative>
           Good to hear that ! I will check with my friends. 
          Great ! cant wait to have a match. Great players match...lol. 
          Lets do it in the evening saturday.
          Remember we have a match.We will wait for you guys.
        </affirmative>
        <negative>
           Its ok if you are busy. I totally understand.
           Cant believe you didnt like the idea. You dont want to play soccer.. WOW ! what about watching MLS.
           Thats fine. We can reschedule it next time. Meanwhile we can watch some match onscreen.     
        </negative>
        <unknown>
           Just let me know when you feel like you want to talk about our match. I am always down for this!.
        </unknown>
        <possibleaffirmatives>
           great
           awesome
           good
           free
           ok
           yes
        </possibleaffirmatives>
        <possiblenegatives>
          bad
          busy
          work
          no
        </possiblenegatives>
        <memorythreshold>
            1
        </memorythreshold>
        <exceededmemory>
            I guess we talked about our match. Lets talk about general stufss now dude!
            cmon we have our match coming. Lets get out of it and talk about MLS.
        </exceededmemory>
    </record>
    
	<record>
	<keyword>
	history
	facts
	figures
	</keyword>
	<phrase>
	  the history
	  the facts
	  the figures
	</phrase>
	<response>
	Did you know the football were made from inflated pig bladders? funny hah .
	The history of soccer can be traced back to 3,000 years. Its pretty old dude !
	Did you know the first video to reach 1 million view was with ronaldihno showing his soccer skills.
	The game was originated in England first. Lots of league games are playe there.
	Before the year 1891, football boots weren’t in use. Instead, the players wore work boots.
	</response>
	</record>
	<record>
	<keyword>
	news
	information
	rumour
	update
	updates
	affair
	</keyword>
	<phrase>
	 the breaking news
	 the current news
	 the current affairs
	</phrase>
	<response>
	US National team recently make a draw of 1-1 with New Zealand. You guys could have done better.
	EL classico for 2016 is set to be in December. The president wants to have more viewers as possible.
	lionel messi was rumoured to be in Real Madrid.Also, Neymar refused to leave barcelona.
	The breaking news: I am going to Europe to see the match in stadium. Ohhh..I cant believe i am doing that.
	Footballers have affairs with beautiful girls. I wish i was a footballer. haha..
	If you want to learn more about football, go to goal.com. Information  there.
	Keep updated with football through facebook pages.
	</response>
	</record>
	<record>
	<keyword>
	america
	soccer
	MLS
	US
	</keyword>
	<phrase>
	Major Soccer League
	the MLS
	the america
	the soccer
	hands
	hand
	</phrase>
	<response>
	    Please say it football not soccer. :)
	Why do you call it soccer ? World says it football so do i. You guys are crazy !
	You play football with your hands. Thats funny hahaha.. 
	American soccer in women is doing great. They were the champions last year.
	Soccer is getting popular these days in US.
	Do you know anything about MLS? If you dont get the hell out of here.... I am just kidding.. lol
	The first American professional soccer league, the USSA, played from 1919 to 1921 and paid 35 cents to every players for scoring. Interesting huh !
	Soccer was illegal in Mississippi until 1991. Crazy people !
	</response>
	<record>
	    <keyword>
	        weather
	        rain
	    </keyword>
	    <phrase>
	       the weather
	       the rain
	    </phrase>
	    <response>
	       The weather looks great to play soccer. You like rain? i love it
	       Its likely to rain today. I will watch league final today.
	    </response>
	</record>
	<record>
	    <keyword>
	        rules
	        empire
	        foul
	    </keyword>
	    <phrase>
	        rules
	        empire
	        game
	        foul
	    </phrase>
	    <response>
	        Game is played ninety minutes. Half time each 45 min. You need to be physically fit.
	        We have a empire and 11 players in each team. Sometimes the games get dirty. Messi got injured!
	        Refree has yellow and red cards. Madrid players got many yellow cards for fouls.
	        The ball is out of play when it fully crosses either the goal line or the touch line.
	        Foul is given when player kicks or attempts to kick an opponent. You should see Madrid players. God! they are brutal!
	    </response>
	</record>
	</record>
		<record>
			<keyword>
				pitch
				arena
				stadium
			</keyword>
			<phrase>
			    the pitch
			    the stadium
			    the match
			    the religion
			</phrase>
			<response>
				You don’t seem to know much about soccer. Did not you play?
				Did you watch the recent match?
				The stadium is too big .. The stadium in our university is quite small.
				South American football is fun to watch. Argentina rocks!
				European leagues are most popular in the world.
				The football is like a religion all over the world. Its a celebration during world cup.
				Messi won fifa Ballon ‘dor 5 times. Ronaldo won it for 3 times.
				The first Clasico of the season between Barcelona and Real Madrid has been scheduled for December 3 at  11:15 a.m. ET (4:15 p.m. CET). Cant wait to see stars.
				Somebody call it pitch but somebody call it arena. You decide what you wanna call it.
			</response>
		</record>
		<record>
			<keyword>
				university
				johnson
				field
				UNM
			</keyword>
			<phrase>
				the johnson field
				 the university pitch
			</phrase>
			<response>
				We can join to play at johnson field if are available. we play every saturday like a star.
				UNM has a cool pitch. They just have to cut grass often.
				I can play soccer. I like playing striker or right winger.
				Pele was the first rocking star of football. He was from brazil.
				That would be wonderful to watch UNM players  playing soccer.
				This rainy weather is great for playing. I like playing in rain in mud. Fun and dirt...
			</response>
		</record>
		<record>
		    <keyword>
		        laliga
			champions
			trophy
		    </keyword>
		<phrase>
		    the champions
		</phrase>
		<response>
		    Barcelona is great ! What do you think of other teams?
			Real madrid has a large fan followings.
			Laliga wants to attract more viewers for the upcoming El classico.
			Did you get the recent news?
		</response>
		</record>
		<record>
			<keyword>
			premier
			leagues
			league
			goal
			goals
			trophy
			trophies
			club
			</keyword>
			<phrase>
				premier league
				the Europe
				the European league
				the goal
				the champions
				the trophy
			</phrase>
			<response>
				Atletico madrid won the champions league 2015.
				I love Juventus.Even more i love Andres pirlo? any other players
				Ronalodo is goal machine. Messi is great ? who do you think is better?
				European are fast and play team game. South american play individually usually.
				Manchester United beated Chelsea by 2-1. Rooney was the star of the game.
				Muller had the record of highest world cup goals which was surprassed by Ronaldo from brazil. He had 15. 
			</response>
		</record>
		<record>
			<keyword>
				messi
				ronaldo
				maradona
				pele
				pirlo
				player
				star
				legend
				classico
			</keyword>
			<phrase>
				great player
				football star
			</phrase>
			<response>
				Pele is a legend of football. He contributed to win 3 worldcup in his career.
				Maradona is the greatest star so far we know. Messi or Ronaldo?
				 Argentina won because of maradona in 1986.
				Many say Messi is the greatest player of all time. No world cup though.
				I love Andres pirlo. he played for Juventus. Do you watch leagues?
				Ronalidhno succedeed more than 6 nutmegs in game against AC milan.
				Who do you think Maradona plays for? .. I mean country
				Brazillian ronaldo has been fifa player of the year for 3 times. any player you like?
				A professional soccer player runs 48 kilometers, or 3.9 miles, in an average soccer game.
			</response>
		</record>
		<record>
		    <keyword>
		        argentina
				brazil
				country
		    </keyword>
		    <phrase>
		        the country
		        </phrase>
		        <response>
		            Brazil won it for five times, Germany 4 and italy 3
		            South American games are different from european ones.
		            I wish world cup was played in our country.
		            Argentina rocks !! They are going to win the another cup .
		        </response>
		</record>
		<record>
			<keyword>
				world
				cup
				worldcup
				fifa
			</keyword>
			<phrase>
				the world cup
				the country
				the fifa
				the cup
			</phrase>
			<response>
				First time world cup was played in two countries in 2002. Japan and South korea.
				World cup is played every four years and is the biggest tournament of world.
				World cup the most celebrated festival of football.
				Ronaldihno was the showman of the football. His dribbling is spectucalar.You should see that.
				Worldcup is played every four years.
				Fifa is the worlds largest organization, even greater than UNO itself. Did you know this?
				The Organziation FIFA was established in the year 1904
			</response>
		</record>
		
	</class>
	<!--if response not found then we look for unknown ones with the specified 
		keywords, if found return else return any random unknow response -->
	<unknownresponse>
	 <response>
		Well, you should not have said that.Somebody might get offended.
		I think you need a little bit of light here. You should probably watch more match.
		I dont know what people talk. I feel like i am dying. I need football drink now!
		I am happy you didnt mention presidential debate. Trump sucks !
		Its boring day. I got lots of homework to do. I will miss the premier league.
		I like this rainy weather. Football in rain. WOW !!
		nah, dont say that. You can be a great footballer.
		I dont like talking about anything else except football
		Football runs in my blood.
		I dont care about food if i am playing. 
		I get a good sleep after i play football. 
		I am sleeping for more than 8 hours nowadays.I play football almost everyday.
		I don’t understand it. Can you rephrase it ? sorry i am not good in english.
		Now, dont say that earth is round...
		I didnot expect this. Lets move on to something else!
		Using soccer or football means same to me. It doesnot really matter.
		When i will have my home, i wish to have my own soccer pitch. 
		I don't know what you are saying? I just speak football
		I want you to join a soccer club for me.
		I like girls playing soccer. I wish i could marry footballers lol.
		</response>
	</unknownresponse>
	 <defaultaffirmatives>
        <defaultaffirmatives>
            yes
            yup
            yep
            yeah
            ya
        </defaultaffirmatives>
    </defaultaffirmatives>
    <defaultnegatives>
        <defaultnegatives>
            no
            nope
            nah
            na
            never
        </defaultnegatives>
    </defaultnegatives>
	<defaultresponse>
	 <defaultresponse>
	Glad ! we are talking. Cant wait to go to pitch now. I mean UNM pitch. Have you ever played there?
	We should talk about it more. We speak football .. lol. Don't we? 
	I hope you are doing well with studies. But keep your boots on.
	I hope you had a good sleep. You look fresh and content. Did you win some game or what?
	Great things happening around ! We have UNM soccer match tomorrow. You wanna attend it.
	We should grab lunch time sometime ! We can talk about football more than !
	</defaultresponse>
	</defaultresponse>
</data>

